
export const quizQuestions_6 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'What is the primary purpose of the map() function in React for rendering lists?',
    choices: ['To iterate over an array and modify its elements', 'To create a new array by applying a function to each element', 'To loop through an array and render components for each element', 'To filter elements based on a given condition'],
    correctAnswer: 'To loop through an array and render components for each element',
  },
  {
    question: 'Why is it important to provide a unique "key" prop when rendering lists in React?',
    choices: ['To enhance the performance of list rendering', 'To satisfy Reacts syntax requirements', 'To avoid warning messages in the console', 'To identify each list item and update efficiently'],
    correctAnswer: 'To identify each list item and update efficiently',
  },
  {
    question: 'In React, where should the "key" prop be specified when rendering a list of elements?',
    choices: ['On the parent component', 'On each child component in the list', 'As a global variable in the component', 'In the state object'],
    correctAnswer: 'On each child component in the list',
  },
  {
    question: 'What happens if you do not provide a "key" prop when rendering a list in React?',
    choices: ['React will automatically generate a key', 'The list will not render', 'It will not affect the rendering process', 'A warning will be logged to the console'],
    correctAnswer: 'A warning will be logged to the console',
  },
  {
    question: 'When rendering a list in React, what should be avoided as a key?',
    choices: ['Index of the element in the array', 'Unique identifiers associated with each element', 'Randomly generated strings', 'Any string value'],
    correctAnswer: 'Index of the element in the array',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the purpose of the "index" argument in the map() function when rendering a list?',
    choices: ['To provide an alternative key for the list elements', 'To access the current element in the iteration', 'To specify the position of the element in the array', 'To determine the total number of elements in the array'],
    correctAnswer: 'To specify the position of the element in the array',
  },
  {
    question: 'In React, how can you conditionally render list items based on a specific condition?',
    choices: ['By using the filter() method on the array', 'By using the conditional (ternary) operator in the map() function', 'By using the switch statement in the map() function', 'It is not possible to conditionally render list items'],
    correctAnswer: 'By using the conditional (ternary) operator in the map() function',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which React hook is commonly used for handling state in components rendering lists?',
    choices: ['useEffect', 'useContext', 'useState', 'useReducer'],
    correctAnswer: 'useState',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the purpose of the "children" prop in React components?',
    choices: ['To define child components', 'To pass data to child components', 'To access the child components directly', 'To render content passed between opening and closing tags of a component'],
    correctAnswer: 'To render content passed between opening and closing tags of a component',
  },
  {
    question: 'In React, how can you optimize the rendering performance of a list with dynamic elements?',
    choices: ['By using the memoization technique', 'By increasing the size of the list', 'By using the "forceUpdate" method', 'By setting the "key" prop to null'],
    correctAnswer: 'By using the memoization technique',
    },
  ],
}